<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lars Wagoner</title>
    <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lars Wagoner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 23:18:40 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.larswagoner.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Finitely Generated Modules over a PID</title>
      <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/finitely-generated-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 23:18:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/finitely-generated-modules/</guid>
      <description>In this project for the &amp;ldquo;Honours Programme&amp;rdquo; I studied and presented The Fundamental Theorem for Finitely Generated Modules over a Principal Ideal Domain, along with the relevant lemmas, corollaries and algorithms. In particular, I deduced and presented an algorithm to determine the structure of a module M in terms of the direct sums of quotient modules of a Euclidean Domain, R.
Contact me if you are interested the paper!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deriving the Black-Scholes Formula</title>
      <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/black-scholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/black-scholes/</guid>
      <description>In this project, we derive the Black-Scholes formula and apply it to real world options. In order to tackle the challenge of anticipating the behavior of the option market, a binomial model is obtained. The aforementioned model is the foundation upon which the Black-Scholes formula for European option pricing is developed. At the end, an analysis on the reliability of Black-Scholes will be implemented using real world data.
You can find the introduction below, contact me if you are interested in other parts of the paper!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combinatorial Group Theory</title>
      <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/comb-group-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 23:16:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/comb-group-theory/</guid>
      <description>In late 2021, I had the absolute pleasure to do an independent study as a part of the &amp;ldquo;Honours Programme&amp;rdquo; at my university. My topic of choice was Combinatorial Group Theory which, roughly speaking, studies groups from their presentations. In the paper, I formally define what a group presentation is (based off of the Free Group on a set) and give several other important definitions. I gave particular emphasis to a nice set of tools called Tietze Transformations, which I used later in the paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now</title>
      <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/now/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 02:11:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.larswagoner.com/now/</guid>
      <description>This is my now page, where I share what I&amp;rsquo;m up to right now. You can read more here.
 Studying mathematics in Amsterdam, with focus on algebra and geometry. Teaching assistant for a few first year courses (most recently, Group Theory). Playing basketball, going bouldering and mostly being bad at both! Sunset strolls in the nearby parks are a personal favorite. Trying to work through my evergrowing collection of books (Antonio Azorín stands out).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 02:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.larswagoner.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello! I&amp;rsquo;m Lars.
I grew up in Spain but I currently live in Amsterdam. I can speak English and Spanish fluently, my French is probably not that bad, my Italian is decent if you don&amp;rsquo;t speak Italian, and my Dutch is embarassingly weak. In general, I find mathematics and related fields interesting, in particular the intersection between pure math and AI. I spend a good amount of time reading (basically anything), so I will gladly accept any recommendations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Malaria &amp; Genetic Modification</title>
      <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/malaria-genetic-modification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/malaria-genetic-modification/</guid>
      <description>In this paper written in mid 2021, we presented the standard model for malaria based on an SIR model. The funnest part, however, was generalizing this model to include the introduction of genetically modified mosquitoes into the system. The idea for this generalization is rooted in this Nature article, that covers how genetically modified male mosquitoes can potentially reduce the spread of vector borne diseases, in particular malaria. Of course, we made some simplifications and assumptions but the end result was a complete success!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Card Game - Casino.py</title>
      <link>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/casino-card-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.larswagoner.com/posts/casino-card-game/</guid>
      <description>I learned how to play Casino, the card game, many years ago while traveling through Thailand. I played it intermitently over the years but I thought it would make for a fun programming project, so a friend and I spent a few weeks in 2021 making a version of the card game playable from the terminal! The current version works if you know how to play (this video has the instructions) and we even added some extra bells and whistles, but of course it could be tidied up a bit and given a graphical interface, but that is low priority for now.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
